Guide to the William Bush Baer Papers MC.46
New York University Archives
William Bush Baer Papers
1944-1958
New York University Archives
Baer, William Bush, 1902-1958
Green Room Honor Society
MC.46
0.75 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, and 1 half manuscript box.
William Bush Baer was an instructor in English at the New York University College of Arts and Sciences in 1926, and was eventually promoted to dean in January of 1942. Beginning in 1952, Dean Baer wrote, produced, and performed in the 15-minute, Sunday morning television program called "Our Goodly Heritage" on WCBS-TV. The collection consists of materials related to Baer's telecasted educational program "Our Goodly Heritage", and materials Baer created and gathered while working at New York University. Collection materials include correspondence, press releases, news clippings, and typescripts. Materials date from 1944 to 1958.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Green Room Honor Society at an unknown date. There is no accession record associated with this collection.
Arrangement
The William Bush Baer papers are arranged according to format. Within each format, materials are arranged chronologically.
Biographical Note
William Bush Baer was born in Peoria, Illinois, in 1902. He obtained his bachelor's degree in 1924 from Hamilton College in Clinton, New York, and his master's degree in 1926 from Harvard University.
Baer joined the New York University faculty as an instructor in English at the NYU College of Arts and Sciences in 1926. He was promoted to assistant professor of English in 1938, associate professor in 1945, and full professor in 1949. Meanwhile, he had been named counselor of studies at the College in 1930, assistant dean in 1934, and dean in January of 1942.
Beginning in 1952, Dean Baer wrote, produced, and performed in the 15-minute, Sunday morning television program called "Our Goodly Heritage" on WCBS-TV. The series was patterned after Baer's course on the Bible as literature.
Related Materials
For photos of Baer, see the NYU Archives "Portrait Files."
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection consists of materials related to Baer's telecasted educational program on WCBS-TV called "Our Goodly Heritage." To a lesser extent, the collection contains materials Baer created and gathered while working at New York University. Collection materials include correspondence, press releases, news clippings, and typescripts. Materials date from 1944 to 1958.
English teachers.; Television producers and directors.; Green Room Honor Society; New York University. College of Arts and Science; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; WCBS-TV (Television station: New York, N.Y.)
- Correspondence, 1944, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Press Releases, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Listings of 112 Typescripts on "Our Goodly Heritage", 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1952 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1953 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1955 January - July (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1955 September - December (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1956 January - June (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1956 July - December (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1957 January - May (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Typescripts [annotated], 1957 June - December (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Typescripts of "Our Goodly Heritage", 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)